<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ratio on Maya Sarangan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ratio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ratio on Maya Sarangan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 20:58:20 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ratio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A4 Paper Has a Superpower… and It’s Pure Math</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/math-and-paper-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 20:58:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/math-and-paper-size/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Math is everywhere, even in places you will not expect it to be in. It might even be in the sheet of paper that you use everyday&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever looked down at your desk and tried to find out the dimensions of your paper? Most people do not, but I can change your mind about that. Let us start with the size of A4 paper. The dimensions of A4 paper are 210 mm x 297 mm. But, why? Why is it that A4 paper has to be of those dimensions? Why not 225 mm x 325 mm. Or 765 mm x 150 mm. That is what I am going to explain, along with many other things today. Let&amp;rsquo;s start!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euclidean Simplification - Math Trick or Magical Treat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/math-trick-or-magical-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:49:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/math-trick-or-magical-treat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trick - or - treating is one of the best times of the year.You get a wide assortment of candies and chocolates. But, what about the tricks? No one ever gives out tricks! So, for halloween I will be giving you a very special trick, a math trick! I promise, the way it gets the solution… You will have a magical treat….&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, let’s talk about what this trick is used for, it is used for simplifying fractions! Simplifying fractions is when you take a fraction and decrease it until it is at its lowest form. Let me give you an example:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ratios, Tables, and One Very Proud 90’s Kid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/table-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:11:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/table-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This method never failed me in 25 years!!!&amp;rdquo;, declared my dad. He is a 90&amp;rsquo;s kid. You know, the kids who had a secret crush on their teachers(yikes), who played with Tamagotchi(seriously?), who thought the world was simple and beautiful(spoiler alert: it wasn&amp;rsquo;t!) back then, and their old - school method of studying is better(not always).But, I have to agree there are instances where some of their methods are easy to understand and surprisingly useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
