<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contents on Maya Sarangan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/content/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contents on Maya Sarangan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:49:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Euclidean Simplification - Math Trick or Magical Treat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/math-trick-or-magical-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:49:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/math-trick-or-magical-treat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trick - or - treating is one of the best times of the year.You get a wide assortment of candies and chocolates. But, what about the tricks? No one ever gives out tricks! So, for halloween I will be giving you a very special trick, a math trick! I promise, the way it gets the solution… You will have a magical treat….&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, let’s talk about what this trick is used for, it is used for simplifying fractions! Simplifying fractions is when you take a fraction and decrease it until it is at its lowest form. Let me give you an example:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ratios, Tables, and One Very Proud 90’s Kid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/table-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:11:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/table-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This method never failed me in 25 years!!!&amp;rdquo;, declared my dad. He is a 90&amp;rsquo;s kid. You know, the kids who had a secret crush on their teachers(yikes), who played with Tamagotchi(seriously?), who thought the world was simple and beautiful(spoiler alert: it wasn&amp;rsquo;t!) back then, and their old - school method of studying is better(not always).But, I have to agree there are instances where some of their methods are easy to understand and surprisingly useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Fun Ways to Multiply (Without a Calculator!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/multiplication-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:34:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/content/posts/multiplication-strategies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had an interesting conversation with my friends. It was about different types of multiplication. Surprisingly, they knew only one method of multiplication and in one case did not understand the underlying meaning of multiplication. So, I explained to them the five methods that I knew.I thought it would be great to share this knowledge with others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;method-1repetitive-addition&#34;&gt;Method 1:Repetitive Addition&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first method is called &amp;ldquo;repetitive addition&amp;rdquo;. In fact,this explains the underlying meaning of multiplication. In this method we simply write out our multiplication equation in terms of addition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
